二零二二年山西省学业水平考试
英语听力。
一情景反应。
本题共五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话，请你从每小题所。
给的
,B 1. Andy, you really like eating apples.
三幅图片中，选出与你所听到的信息相关联的一项，并在答题卡上将该项
涂黑。
每小题读两遍。
Don't you know, an apple a day keeps the doctor away?
2. Have you ever been to the Great Wall?
Of course, it's one of the symbols of China.
3. Excuse me, what can I do for you?
I need a school bag for my son.
He will start school.
4. Look at the big tiger over there.
Oh, how strong it is!
5. It's so hot, let's go swimming.
Great! I can't wait to jump into the water.
2. B, 6.
二，对话理解。
本题共五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话和一个问题，请你从每小题所
给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
每小题读两遍。
Peter, what's your dream job?
My parents want me to be a doctor or an engineer, but I want to be a cook.
7. What does Peter want to be?
Peter, what's your dream job?
My parents want me to be a doctor or an engineer, but I want to be a cook.
Question. does Peter want to be?
7. Frank, when shall we see the movie?
On Friday or Saturday?
I'm not free these days.
Let's go on Sunday.
Question. When are they going to see the movie?
Frank, when shall we see the movie?
On Friday or Saturday?
I'm not free these days.
Let's go on Sunday.
Question. When are they going to see the movie?
8. You arrived so early.
Did you drive your car here?
No, I took the subway.
It's faster. Question.
How did the man come here?
9. Good morning, Mr.
Wu, everyone is here now.
Okay, let's begin our class.
Question. Where are the two speakers?
Good morning, Mr.
Wu. Everyone is here now.
Okay, let's begin our class.
Question. Where are the two speakers?
10. you like to join us in camping this weekend?
I'm afraid not.
I just want to stay at home with my family.
Question. What does the man mean?
3. My name is Mike.
三，语篇理解。
本题你将听到一篇短文，请你根据短文内容和所提出的五个问题，从。一
小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
短文读两遍。
I have a twin brother, Sam.
When we were 10 years old, Mom sent us to take piano lessons.
Sam was very smart and learned everything quickly.
Soon, he was able to play some beautiful piano music.
The teacher loved him.
I wanted to be like him.
A year later, we took part in a piano competition.
I had practiced as hard as I could, but the grade was not as good as I had expected.
It was far from what Sam had got.
I was so sad.
Then, Mom came up to me.
You will do better next time, Mike, she said.
I shook my head and said, I will never be like Sam, no matter how hard I work.
She shook her head and said softly,
No, you don't have to be like Sam.
You just have to be the best Mike the world has ever seen.
After the talk, gradually, I understood what these words really meant.
That had been my goal ever since.
Although I couldn't become that excellent like Sam, it didn't matter.
Because I knew I only needed to be the best myself through hard work.
My name is Mike.
I have a twin brother, Sam.
When we were 10 years old, Mom sent us to take piano lessons.
Sam was very smart and learned everything quickly.
Soon he was able to play some beautiful piano music.
The teacher loved him.
I wanted to be like him.
A year later, we took part in a piano competition.
I had practiced as hard as I could, but the grade was not as good as I had expected.
It was far from what Sam had got.
I was so sad.
Then, Mom came up to me.
You will do better next time, Mike, she said.
I shook my head and said, I will never be like Sam, no matter how hard I work.
She shook her head and said softly,
No, you don't have to be like Sam.
You just have to be the best Mike the world has ever seen.
After the talk, gradually, I understood what these words really meant.
That had been my goal ever since.
Although I couldn't become that excellent like Sam, it didn't matter.
Because I knew I only needed to be the best myself through hard work.
四，听力填空。
the Li Hua, a senior high school student from grade 2.
本题你将听到一篇演讲词，请你根据所听内容完成下面的句子，并将获取
的信息填到答题卡相应的位置上，每空一词。
短文读两遍。
Congratulations! You will soon come to senior high school.
How can you spend the time in high school?
It's a problem.
Now, I'll give you some advice.
First, work hard.
As for schoolwork, senior high school may not seem different.
Second, also has teachers, books, homework, and exams, so you're supposed to still
work hard. Second, manage your time wisely.
You might have more difficult schoolwork and self -study time at night, but try to
finish your homework quickly and get enough sleep.
Third, don't compare yourself to others.
In your class, there might be many top students.
Pay attention to your own work, and don't push yourself too much.
Last but not least, stay active.
High school teachers will not take care of you all the time, like in junior high
school. You need to have your own plans.
Don't be lazy.
Well, these are the big secrets about high school.
Good luck, and hope you have a good time.
Thank you so much.
Hello, everyone. Thank you for being here for my speech.
I'm Li Hua, a senior high school student from grade two.
Congratulations! You will soon come to senior high school.
How can you spend the time in high school?
It's a problem.
Now, I'll give you some advice.
First, work hard.
As for schoolwork, senior high school may not seem different.
It also has teachers, books, homework, and exams, so you're supposed to still work
hard. Second, manage your time wisely.
You might have more difficult schoolwork and self -study time at night, but try to
finish your homework quickly and get enough sleep.
Third, don't compare yourself to others.
In your class, there might be many top students.
Pay attention to your own work, and don't push yourself too much.
Last but not least, stay active.
High school teachers will not take care of you all the time, like in junior high
school. You need to have your own plans.
Don't be lazy.
Well, these are the big secrets about high school.
Good luck, and hope you have a good time.
Thank you so much.
听力测试结束，请关注“锦鲤英语”微信公众号